University Chaplaincy Records UA116
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
University Chaplaincy Records
circa 1865 -- 2021
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
University Chaplaincy
UA116
13.95 Linear Feet
1 Web sites
5.6 Gigabytes
32 Digital Object(s)
This collection contains materials created by or associated with the University Chaplaincy, documenting programming and events, the work of specific chaplains and chaplaincies, the history of Goddard Chapel, the history of religion at Tufts, and the Chaplaincy's outreach efforts.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the University Chaplaincy, 2018, accession UA-2019-002; 2020, accession UA-2021-019; 2021, accessions UA-2021-034 and UA-2022-029.
Arrangement
This collection consists of five series: Web crawls; 2018 accessions; Unprocessed accessions; Born digital materials; and 2020 -- 2021 accessions.
Biographical / Historical
Edwin Courtlandt Bolles was made the first chaplain of the university in 1905. Today, the Tufts Chaplaincy is committed to modeling interreligious harmony and well-being at Tufts. Each chaplain serves those who are in his, her, or their tradition through regular worship and other programs. Valuing pluralism and multiculturalism, it educates tomorrow's leaders for global citizenship by actively encouraging dialogue and cooperation among the wide variety of religious traditions on the campuses.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials created by or associated with the University Chaplaincy. Materials include correspondence, publications, fliers, newsletters, photographs and slides, hymnals and song books, VHS and cassette tapes, born digital audio, video, and photographic materials, as well as web crawls of the Tufts University Chaplaincy website. The collection documents Chaplaincy programming and events and Chaplaincy participation in University events, the work of specific chaplains and chaplaincies, the history of Goddard Chapel, the history of religion at Tufts, and the Chaplaincy's outreach efforts.
Goddard Chapel; Religious life; Religious education; Student Affairs and Services; Student life; Student activism; Protestant Chaplaincy; Muslim Chaplaincy; Catholic Chaplaincy
- Web crawls, 2015 -- 2020; UA116.001; 1 Web sites
  Scope and Contents
  Quarterly web crawls of the Tufts University Chaplaincy website crawled by DCA, as part of the Student Organizations web collection, to document the presesence of Tufts University student organizations on the web.
  Other Finding Aids
  To see all of websites crawled as part of the Student Organizations web collection, please visit https://archive-it.org/collections/6387
  - Tufts University Chaplaincy, 2015 -- 2020; UA116.001.00001
    Conditions Governing Access
    Open for research.
    General
    Frequency: quarterly crawl.
- 2018 accessions, circa 1865 -- 2018; UA116.002; 1.55 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged roughly by format. Original order was maintained.
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by the University Chaplaincy, 2018, accession UA-2019-002.
  This series contains fliers and other material documenting Chaplaincy programming, including concerts, speakers, and participation in university and other events, as well as correspondence, fliers, and other materials documenting specific chaplains and chaplaincies. This series also contains publications, photographs, slides of Goddard Chapel, VHS tapes, and cassettes. VHS tapes document a memorial service for Allan Cormack; the 2002 University Baccalaureate Service; and the lecture "Sources of Hope for a Global Future" by Desmond Tutu. Cassette tapes document the Goddard Chapel Forum; the 1995 Interfaith Forum; the 1999 Book Forum; Dean David Maxwell in 1986;, and Jane Redmont in 1993.
  - Goddard Talk Newsletter, 2003 -- 2013; UA116.002.001.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Goddard Chapel, 1964 -- 2013; UA116.002.001.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    20 years from date of creation.
  - Muslim Chaplaincy, 1988 -- 2013; UA116.002.001.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Protestant Chaplaincy, 1986 -- 2013; UA116.002.001.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Episcopal Chaplaincy, 1941 -- 1995; UA116.002.001.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Catholic Chaplaincy, 1987 -- 2003; UA116.002.001.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Humanist Chaplaincy, 2011 -- 2018; UA116.002.001.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - William (Scotty) McLennan, 1987 -- 2000; UA116.002.001.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - David M. O'Leary, 2011; UA116.002.001.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Christmas Holiday Concert, 1990 -- 2012; UA116.002.001.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Concerts in Goddard Chapel, 1980 -- 2013; UA116.002.001.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Noontime concerts, 1983 -- 2013; UA116.002.001.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Memorial of Chancellor Jean Mayer, 1992 -- 1993; UA116.002.001.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Commencement, 1865 -- 2016; UA116.002.001.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 9/11 Memorial materials, 2001 -- 2011; UA116.002.001.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - MLK Jr Celebration Day, 1986 -- 2017; UA116.002.001.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Interfaith related material, 1995 -- 2013; UA116.002.001.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Goddard Chapel Forum, 2000 -- 2013; UA116.002.001.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Chaplaincy programming flyers, 2000 -- 2016; UA116.002.001.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Chaplain's Table, 1983 -- 2008; UA116.002.001.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Reflections, 1996 -- 2006; UA116.002.001.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Café Pre-Orientation, 2009; UA116.002.001.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Non-Chaplaincy programs in Goddard Chapel, 1997 -- 2012; UA116.002.001.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous flyers, clippings, and photographs, 1979 -- 2018; UA116.002.001.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Slides and media, 1986 -- 2002; UA116.002.002; .35 Linear Feet (Box 2)
    This file contains slides of Goddard Chapel; VHS tapes of a memorial service for Allan Cormack, the 2002 University Baccalaureate Service, and the lecture "Sources of Hope for a Global Future" by Desmond Tutu; and cassette tapes of the Goddard Chapel Forum, the 1995 Interfaith Forum, the 1999 Book Forum, Dean David Maxwell in 1986, and Jane Redmont in 1993.
- Additional accessions, 1910 -- 2015; UA116.003
  - Baccalaureate programs, history of religion at Tufts, 1996 -- 2003; UA116-001 (Box 1)
  - Chapel History, 1910 -- 1984; UA116-002 (Box 2)
  - Outreach materials, 2015; UA116-003 (Box 3)
    Brochures, flyers, and postcards
- Born digital materials, 2002 -- 2013; UA116.004; 4.614 Gigabytes; 9 Digital Object(s) 9 digital objects comprising 93 files.
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
  This series contains video, audio, and photographic documentation of events held or attended by the Chaplaincy including the Goddard Chapel Forum, the Baccalaureate Service, and the Russell Lecture. This series also contains excel spreadsheets and word documents related to the Chaplaincy budget.
  Records on digital media that are open for research have been stabilized and made available via Box. Note that files were not converted for access and all may not be viewable in Box. Please contact DCA for further details.
  - Singing for Sudan, 2013; UA116.004.00001; 5 Digital Object(s); 108 Megabytes
    Video on the original media of this file did not work; only audio is available for this file.
  - Russell Lecture, 2013; UA116.004.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 3 Gigabytes
  - Chaplaincy budget, 2008 -- 2010; UA116.004.00003; 85 Digital Object(s); 13.6 Megabytes
    20 years from the date of creation.
    Excel spreadsheets and word documents relating to the Chaplaincy's budget from 2008-2010.
  - Ingrid Matson transcript, 2005; UA116.004.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 630.2 Megabytes
  - Goddard Chapel Forum: Ambassador Grover Rees, 2008; UA116.004.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); 339.4 Megabytes
  - Chaplains at Baccalaureate, 2009; UA116.004.00006; 16 Digital Object(s); 70.6 Megabytes
  - Goddard Chapel Forum, 2011; UA116.004.00007; 13 Digital Object(s); 132.2 Megabytes
  - Goddard Chapel Forum: Archbishop Demetrios, 2011; UA116.004.00008; 11 Digital Object(s); 104.5 Megabytes
  - Desmond Tutu at Tufts, 2002; UA116.004.00009; 60 Digital Object(s); 270 Megabytes
- 2020 -- 2021 accessions, 1884 -- 2021; UA116.005; 1.0 Gigabytes; 23 Digital Object(s); 8.2 Linear Feet
  Transferred by the Tufts University Chaplaincy, 2020 -- 2021, accessions UA-2021-019, UA-2021-034, UA-2021-056, and UA-2022-029.
  This series contains annual newsletters from the Buddhist, Catholic, Humanist, Muslim, and Protestant chaplaincies from 2015 through the 2020/2021 academic year, as well as event fliers, posters, and recordings; scrapbooks of newspaper clippings that relate to Chaplaincy activities; songbooks, hymnals, and organ music from Goddard Chapel; and other Goddard Chapel records.
  - Tufts Muslim Life Newsletter, 2015; 1436 Hijri; UA116.000045; 6.1 Megabytes
  - Muslim Chaplaincy Newsletter, Summer 2016; Summer 1437 Hijri; UA116.000046; 921.4 Kilobytes
  - Catholic Chaplaincy Newsletter, Summer 2017; UA116.000047; 2 Megabytes
  - Humanist Chaplaincy Newsletter, Summer 2017; UA116.000048; 2 Megabytes (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Muslim Chaplaincy Newsletter, Spring 2017; Spring 1438 Hijri; UA116.000049; 5 Megabytes
  - Protestant Chaplaincy Newsletter, Summer 2017; UA116.000050; 2.2 Megabytes
  - Buddhist Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2018; UA116.000051; 3.2 Megabytes
  - Catholic Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2018; UA116.000052; 2.6 Megabytes
  - Humanist Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2018; UA116.000053; 2 Megabytes (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Muslim Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2018; 1439 Hijri; UA116.000054; 4.3 Megabytes
  - Protestant Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2018; UA116.000055; 3.3 Megabytes
  - Catholic Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2019 -- 2020; UA116.000056; 2.6 Megabytes
  - Humanist Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2019 -- 2020; UA116.000057; 3.1 Megabytes
  - Protestant Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2019 -- 2020; UA116.000058; 3.5 Megabytes
  - Buddhist Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2020 -- 2021; UA116.000059; 3 Megabytes
  - Catholic Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2020 -- 2021; UA116.000060; 2.2 Megabytes
  - Humanist Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2020 -- 2021; UA116.000061; 2.7 Megabytes (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Muslim Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2020 -- 2021; UA116.000062; 2 Megabytes
  - Protestant Chaplaincy Newsletter, 2020 -- 2021; UA116.000063; 2.8 Megabytes
  - Illumination Ceremony video, 2020; UA116.000064; 539 Megabytes
  - A time to grieve, hope, and act: marking a year since Tufts' campus closure event flyer, 2021 March; UA116.000066; 736.84 Kilobytes
  - A time to grieve, hope, and act: marking a year since Tufts' campus closure event program, 2021 March 07; UA116.000067; 231.24 Kilobytes
  - A time to grieve, hope, and act: marking a year since Tufts' campus closure vigil recording, 2021 March 07; UA116.000068; 408.06 Megabytes
  - Humanist Chaplaincy fliers, 2017 -- 2021; UA116.000069 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "In the Wake of Obama's Hope: Thoughts on Black Lives Matter, Humanism, and Re-imagining Race Struggle" with Dr. Anthony B. Pinn event poster, 2018 April 26; UA116.000070 (Box Shared 137)
  - "Chaplaincy for the 'Nones': Spiritual Care in an Increasingly Nonreligious America" event poster, 2021 April 21; UA116.000071 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1985 -- 1990; UA116.000072 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1990 -- 1994; UA116.000073 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 2000 -- 2003; UA116.000074 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 2002 -- 2009; UA116.000075 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 2009 -- 2011; UA116.000076 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 2011 -- 2012; UA116.000077 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook, 2012 -- 2014; UA116.000078 (Box 6)
  - Event posters and fliers, circa 2010 -- 2020; UA116.000079 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clippings and Baccalaureate Service program, 1993 -- 1995; 2017; UA116.000080 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Goddard Chapel records, 1884 -- 2010; UA116.000081 (Box 7)
    This group of records includes a chapel service book, song books, hymnals, and organ music used in Goddard Chapel, as well as "A Walking Tour of Goddard Chapel," a nine-page account of the history and traditions of the Chapel written by Edwin Rollins and accompanied by related background material. There are also Goddard Chapel masonry and roof repair specifications; slides; a book of Tufts University trivia; annual goals for University Chaplain Scotty McLennan, including related correspondence and memos; a Tufts Alumni pamphlet; and a monograph by William L. McLennan, Jr., Lecturer and Chaplain, Tufts University, "The Story of Business Ethics: Legend and Corporate Ethical Climate."